Eventually, God spoke
to Job from a whirlwind.
God didn’t defend himself
or explain Job’s suffering.
[Music]
Rather, God highlighted the ignorance
of Job and his friends
and posed at least 66 questions.
Job couldn't answer even one.
[Music]
It was as if God
had patiently said to Job,
If you can’t answer
any of my questions about this world,
is it possible that eternal laws
exist that you don't understand?
Are there assumptions
you've made that are invalid?
And can you foresee
your intended future destiny?
[Music]
Job grasped God's message.
He humbly acknowledged
that he hadn't understood.
He recognized that though
all sin causes suffering,
not all suffering is caused by sin.
Because his suffering wasn’t
caused by sin,
Job’s job was to trust God.
Because of his trust in God,
Job learned that “when [God] hath
tried me, I shall come forth as gold,”
and “though he slay me,
yet will I trust . . . him.”
[Music]
Like Job, we need to trust
in our Heavenly Father in Jesus Christ
and remain faithful in all circumstances.
[Music]
Job's testimony of the Savior
is inspiring thousands of years
after he uttered it.
And it's my testimony as well.
[Music]
“Oh that my words were now written!
oh that they were printed in a book!
That they were graven with an iron
pen and lead in the rock for ever!
For I know that my redeemer liveth,
and that he shall stand
at the latter day upon the earth:
And though . . . worms destroy this body,
yet in my flesh shall I see God.”
[Music]
Jesus Christ won't just
console us and restore what was lost,
but He will even consecrate
our afflictions for our gain.
[Music]
The Savior has the power to make
everything right, and He yearns to do so.
[Music]
The ultimate lesson of the book
of Job is that our job, like Job’s,
is to trust God—no matter what.
These teachings encourage us to let
God prevail so that we remain optimistic
and hopeful despite challenges.
In the name of Jesus Christ, amen.